guitarnick.com 2019-06-14

# PRIVACY POLICY and COOKIES - GuitarNick.com

At www.guitarnick.com, the privacy of our visitors is of extreme importance to us. This privacy policy document outlines the types of personal information is received and collected by www.guitarnick.com and how it is used.

GuitarNick.com complies with the new EU e-Privacy Directive Law and uses cookies to improve user experience. By continuing to browse the site, you are agreeing to our use of cookies.

Our website is funded by online advertising. This helps us create new content and keep it free. When you visit our website, your browser automatically sends certain information to our advertising partners. This includes the URL of the page you’re visiting and your IP address.  Our partners can also set cookies on your browser or read cookies that are already there.  
If ad personalization is turned on, our partners will use your information to make your ads more useful for you.  
If ad personalization if off, they will not collect or use your information to personalize the ads shown to you. You will still see ads, but they may not be as useful. Ads may still be based on the topic of the website or app you’re looking at, your current search terms, or on your general location, but not on your interests, search history, or browsing history.

If you require any more information or have any questions about our privacy policy, please feel free to contact us by email at mail@guitarnick.com.

 **AdThrive**  
This Site is affiliated with AdThrive, LLC (“AdThrive”) for the purposes of placing advertising on the Site.  AdThrive uses standard and widely-available tools for the placement and serving of ads, including those provided by Google, Inc. and its affiliates. We publish interest-based advertisements on the Site; that is, ads that are tailored to reflect your interests. To help understand your interests, AdThrive, Google and our other advertising partners will track your behaviour on our website and on other websites across the Internet using cookies. 

A cookie is a file containing an identifier (a string of letters and numbers) that is sent by a web server to a web browser and is stored by the browser. The identifier is then sent back to the server each time the browser requests a page from the server. Cookies may be either "persistent" cookies or "session" cookies: a persistent cookie will be stored by a web browser and will remain valid until its set expiry date, unless deleted by the user before the expiry date; a session cookie, on the other hand, will expire at the end of the user session, when the web browser is closed.  Cookies do not typically contain any information that personally identifies a user, but personal information that we store about you may be linked to the information stored in and obtained from cookies.

By using this Site, you consent to the use of such cookies and the sharing of data captured by such cookies with AdThrive, Google, and our other third party partners. You can view, delete or add interest categories associated with your browser by visiting: [https://adssettings.google.com](https://adssettings.google.com/authenticated). You can also opt out of the network cookie using those settings or using the Network Advertising Initiative's multi-cookie opt-out mechanism at: [http://optout.networkadvertising.org](http://optout.networkadvertising.org/?c=1). However, these opt-out mechanisms themselves use cookies, and if you clear the cookies from your browser your opt-out will not be maintained. 

For European Economic Area Residents

If you reside in a country in the European Economic Area (EEA), then under the GDPR and applicable data protection laws you have the rights, among other things, to access your personal data, have us erase it, and/or restrict its further processing.  If you wish to access or delete your personal data (if any) maintained by us or AdThrive related to advertising on the Site, you can contact us at mail@guitarnick.com and contact AdThrive at info@adthrive.com. If you wish to see a list of the advertising partners we work with or change which of those partners track your behavior using cookies, click the ad preferences link at the bottom of the site. (Available in the EU.)

 **Log Files**  
Like many other Web sites, www.guitarnick.com makes use of log files. The information inside the log files includes internet protocol ( IP ) addresses, type of browser, Internet Service Provider ( ISP ), date/time stamp, referring/exit pages, and number of clicks to analyze trends, administer the site, track user’s movement around the site, and gather demographic information. IP addresses, and other such information are not linked to any information that is personally identifiable. 

Our website uses cookies, as almost all websites do, to help provide you with the best experience we can. Cookies are small text files that are placed on your computer or mobile phone when you browse websites

Our cookies help us:  
Make our website work as you'd expect  
Offer you free services/content (thanks to advertising)  
Improve the speed/security of the site  
Allow you to share pages with social networks like Facebook  
Continuously improve our website for you  
Make our marketing more efficient (ultimately helping us to offer the service we do at the price we do)

We do not use cookies to:  
Collect any personally identifiable information (without your express permission)  
Collect any sensitive information (without your express permission)  
Pass personally identifiable data to third parties  
Pay sales commissions

You can learn more about all the cookies we use below.  
Granting us permission to use cookies  
If the settings on your software that you are using to view this website (your browser) are adjusted to accept cookies, we take this, and your continued use of our website, to mean that you are fine with this. Should you wish to remove or not use cookies from our site you can learn how to do this below, however doing so will likely mean that our site will not work as you would expect.

 **More about our Cookies**  
Social Website Cookies  
So you can easily share our content on the likes of Facebook, Twitter and Google Plus, we have included sharing buttons on our site.

Cookies are set by:

Twitter [https://support.twitter.com/articles/20170514](https://help.twitter.com/en/rules-and-policies/twitter-cookies "Twitter Privacy Policy")  
AddThis <http://www.addthis.com/privacy>  
ShareThis <https://www.sharethis.com/privacy/>  
Facebook <https://www.facebook.com/policies/cookies/>  
Youtube <https://policies.google.com/privacy?hl=en>  
Gooogle Analytics  
<https://policies.google.com/technologies/partner-sites?hl=en>

The privacy implications on this will vary from social network to social network and will be dependent on the privacy settings you have chosen on these networks.

 **Visitor Statistics Cookies**  
We use Google Analitycs cookies to compile visitor statistics, such as how many people have visited our website; what type of technology they are using (e.g. Mac or Windows, which helps to identify when our site isn't working as it should for particular technologies); how long they spend on the site; what page they look at, etc. This helps us to continuously improve our website. These programs also tell us how people reached this site (e.g. from a search engine) and whether they have been here before, helping us to put more money into developing our services for you instead of marketing spend.

 **Advertising Cookies**  
Cookies are widely used in online advertising. We, advertisers or our advertising partners cannot gain personally identifiable information from these cookies.

You can learn more about online advertising at <http://www.youronlinechoices.com/>. You can opt-out of almost all advertising cookies at <http://www.youronlinechoices.com/uk/your-ad-choices>, although we would prefer that you didn't as ultimately adverts help keep much of the internet free. It is also worth noting that opting out of advertising cookies will not mean you won't see adverts, just simply that they won't be tailored to you any longer.

Some of our advertising partners may use cookies and web beacons on our site. Our advertising partners include:

 **Google Adsense**  
We fund our site by showing adverts as you browse our site. These adverts may be managed by a partner specialising in providing adverts for multiple sites. Invariably these partners place cookies to collect anonymous data about the websites you visits so they can personalise the adverts to you, ensure that you don't see the same adverts too frequently and ultimately report to advertisers on which adverts are working.

 **DoubleClick DART Cookie**  
.:: Google, as a third party vendor, uses cookies to serve ads on www.guitarnick.com.  
.:: Google's use of the DART cookie enables it to serve ads to users based on their visit to www.guitarnick.com and other sites on the Internet.  
.:: Users may opt out of the use of the DART cookie by visiting the Google ad and content network privacy policy at the following URL - <https://policies.google.com/technologies/ads?hl=en>  
\- <https://policies.google.com/privacy?hl=en>

**Amazon**  
We are a participant in the Amazon Services LLC Associates Program, an affiliate advertising program designed to provide a means for us to earn fees by linking to Amazon.com and affiliated sites.

These third-party ad servers or ad networks use technology to the advertisements and links that appear on www.guitarnick.com send directly to your browsers. They automatically receive your IP address when this occurs. Other technologies ( such as cookies, JavaScript, or Web Beacons ) may also be used by the third-party ad networks to measure the effectiveness of their advertisements and / or to personalize the advertising content that you see.

www.guitarnick.com has no access to or control over these cookies that are used by third-party advertisers.

You should consult the respective privacy policies of these third-party ad servers for more detailed information on their practices as well as for instructions about how to opt-out of certain practices. www.guitarnick.com's privacy policy does not apply to, and we cannot control the activities of, such other advertisers or web sites.

If you wish to disable cookies, you may do so through your individual browser options. More detailed information about cookie management with specific web browsers can be found at the browsers' respective websites

 **Turning Cookies Off**  
You can usually switch cookies off by adjusting your browser settings to stop it from accepting cookies (learn how here). Doing so, however, will likely limit the functionality of our and a large proportion of the world's websites as cookies are a standard part of most modern websites.

It may be that your concerns around cookies relate to so called 'spyware'. Rather than switching off cookies in your browser, you may find that anti-spyware software achieves the same objective by automatically deleting cookies considered to be invasive. Learn more about managing cookies with antispyware software.

The cookie information text on this site was derived from content provided by Attacat Internet Marketing <https://www.attacat.co.uk/>, a marketing agency based in Edinburgh. If you need similar information for your own website you can use their free cookie audit tool.
